# Kayne Khoury

Phone: (210) 849 - 7083

Email: <u>kaynekhoury1@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>https://github.com/kdk745</u>

I am an Austin, Texas based developer with 5 years of coding experience. My former background is in sales, marketing, and customer service. My primary experience is in backend software programming using Agile development practices.

### **Technical Tools**

Java, JavaScript, Python, .NET, PHP, Scala, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cloud Spanner, Cloud SQL, Google Cloud, Cloud Foundry, AWS, CICD, Unix

## Professional Experience

Software Engineering Consultant, Slalom, May 2018 – April 2019

I provided hands-on software development and engineering for highly-reputable companies in the Austin area. I typically worked with large companies operating in the ecommerce space.

- Redeveloped multiple Spring Boot microservices providing payment authentication and transaction processing.
- Programmed performance tests and standardized implementation to CICD pipelines.
- Unit, Functional, and Integration testing for Spring Boot microservices.
- Developed Express service to provide standardized database query execution and validation.

Software Developer, MyJobMatcher, May 2017 – April 2018

I developed various full-stack web applications while managing and maintaining an architecture of servers and databases. I also provided occasional escalations support for complicated technical issues reported by our clients.

- Developed and maintained recruiting and job-seeking websites programmed in PHP Laravel and Perl.
- Implemented processes to automate the searching, gathering, and saving of publicly posted resumes, and jobs.
- Managed architecture of 100+ cloud servers and 10 rack servers.

Web Application Developer, Corrections Software Inc, June 2016 – April 2017

I provided frequent escalations support for clients while developing web-applications designed to automate job-duties for corrections officers.

- Continuously coded revisions and enhancements for client-specific web-applications based in a custom framework of object-oriented PHP.
- Developed features for in-house Agile board app utilized by clients, client-support team, and programmers.
- Programmed .doc, .ppt, and .pdf document and report generators tailored to client-specific needs utilizing D3 databases, Pick/BASIC scripts, PHP, and RTF.

## Other Experience

Teaching Assistant, Austin Coding Academy and Trilogy Education Services, April 2017 – July 2018

I assisted in proctoring one course focused on full-stack Node.js development and another course on data analytics and visualization. My duties included grading assignments, providing code review and feedback, and assisting students with material during class and office-hours.

#### Education

BA Government, University of Texas at Austin, 2012 – 2016

Elements of Computing Certificate, University of Texas at Austin, 2014 – 2016

The Elements of Computing certificate program offers a set of courses intended to help students understand the sophisticated technologies they use every day as well as gain the computer skills that employers value.

The goals of the program are to:

- Provide students with knowledge of computer science that employers find valuable.
- Support study in other disciplines requiring computational proficiency.

Covered topics include web, mobile, and software programming, data manipulation and visualization, and computer science fundamentals.

Certificate in Advanced Full-Stack Development, Austin Coding Academy, December 2016 – March 2017

This course focused on how to develop full-stack apps in a Node.js environment. Technologies included React, Redux, MongoDB, and Express.